[Music]
[Muzika]
Google announced on Tuesday all of the
Google je u utorak objavio sve
new capabilities is added to its voice
njegovom glasu dodaju se nove mogućnosti
assistant including various additions to
asistent, uključujući razne dodatke za
the way it handles privacy one of these
način na koji se odnosi na privatnost jedan od tih
systems new privacy features will allow
nove mogućnosti privatnosti sistema će dopustiti
users to delete a record of the most
korisnici brišu najviše zapisa
recent command by saying that wasn't for
nedavna naredba rekavši da to nije za
you this means users can delete voice
to znači da korisnici mogu izbrisati glas
recordings immediately if someone else
snimke odmah ako neko drugi
starts at the separate conversation in
započinje u zasebnom razgovoru u
the background or if the user decides
pozadini ili ako korisnik odluči
that what was said should not be shared
da ono što je rečeno ne treba deliti
users can also ask are you saving my
korisnici također mogu pitati spašavate li moju
audio data to learn more about their
audio podaci da biste saznali više o njihovim
privacy controls and to go directly to
kontrola privatnosti i izravno na
the settings screen to change their
ekran s postavkama da biste ih promijenili
preferences as well as delete voice
postavke kao i brisanje glasa
assistant activity from a Google account
pomoćna aktivnost s Google računa
by saying things like quote delete
izgovarajući stvari poput citata izbriši
everything I said to you this week the
sve što sam vam rekao ove nedelje
assistant has had a fair share of
pomoćnik je imao prilično udio u
privacy concerns with Google confirming
brige o privatnosti koje Google potvrđuje
in August that third-party workers were
avgusta bili su treći radnici
systematically listening systematically
sistematski slušati
listening and leaking private touch
slušanje i curenje privatnog dodira
conversations collected by the
razgovori prikupljeni od strane
assistants it had been revealed that
pomoćnici to je otkrilo
more than 1,000 files had been leaked
procurilo je više od 1.000 datoteka
from these workers including recordings
od tih radnika uključujući snimke
so from instances where users
pa iz slučajeva gdje su korisnici
accidentally triggered Google's software
slučajno pokrenuo Googleov softver
after the incident a Google paused all
nakon incidenta Google je sve zaustavio
of its language for a few operations
svog jezika za nekoliko operacija
these new privacy features come not too
ove nove značajke privatnosti također ne dolaze
long after Google decided to revamp its
dugo nakon što je Google odlučio da ga prenovi
assistant privacy policy last year the
pomoćnik politike privatnosti prošle godine
changes from last year included Google
promjene iz prošle godine uključuju i Google
making it default for the voice
čineći ga zadanim za glas
assistant to not retain audio recordings
pomoćnika da ne zadrži audio snimke
a once a request is fulfilled meaning
jednom kada se ispuni zahtjev, znači
that users have to opt in to let Google
koje se korisnici moraju prijaviti da bi dopustili Googleu
keep any voice recordings made by the
čuvajte bilo kakve snimke glasa koje je napravio
device it also added a feature that
uređaj je takođe dodao funkciju koja
allows users to review and delete past
omogućava korisnicima pregled i brisanje prošlosti
historical audio recordings
povijesne audio snimke
besides the security enhancements other
pored sigurnosnih poboljšanja ostalo
additions to the assistant announced by
dodaci za asistenta najavio
Google on Tuesday include the ability to
Google u utorak uključuje mogućnost da
schedule certain
raspored određen
asks for example users that have a
pita za primjer korisnike koji imaju
Google home integrated washer or dryer
Perilica ili sušilica za kućne uređaje tvrtke Google
can schedule a load of laundry with the
možete zakazati puno rublja s
assistant this feature is set to be
pomoćnik za ovu funkciju postavljen
rolled out later this year
objavljen kasnije ove godine
Google has added support for various new
Google je dodao podršku za razne nove
smart device categories such as AC units
kategorije pametnih uređaja kao što su AC jedinice
coffee makers vacuums and smart bathtubs
vakuumi za kavu i pametne kade
among others I would love for my device
između ostalih volio bih svoj uređaj
to be able to make me good coffee oh and
da mi možete dobro kafu oh i
bring it to me I would like to be able
donesi mi to, volio bih da mogu
to run a bath I don't know about the
za kupanje ne znam za to
bath thing and I don't know about the
stvar za kupanje i ne znam za to
anything with water bath and laundry
bilo s vodom i kupatilom
I think I'm against I think it would be
Mislim da sam protiv mislim da bi bilo
cool I know that my neighbor down the
cool znam da je moj komšija dole
street has one of the new like washer
ulica ima jednu od novih poput perilice
and dryer in one machine yep right so if
i sušite u jednoj mašini da, pa ako
you put a load of wash in but you know
stavite puno pranja unutra ali znate
that you're gonna be home from work at a
da ćeš biti kod kuće kod posla
certain time is that stuff to be not
određeno vrijeme je da takvih stvari ne bude
wrinkly just sitting there then you
bora samo tamo sjediš ti
could like turn one into your home scene
mogao bi pretvoriti jedan u vašu domaću scenu
I'm the guy who has had pipes break and
Ja sam tip koji je imao puknute cijevi i
had write things like that happened so
napisao takve stvari
for me it's like I monitor things like I
za mene je to kao da nadgledam takve stvari kao što sam
check on the laundry while it's
provjeri veš dok je
happening right
događa se ispravno
while it's happening I don't run them
dok se dešava ja ih ne vodim
when I'm not home I super trust - yeah
kad nisam kod kuće super mi vjerujem - da
my dad had it happen where the laundry
moj otac se dogodio da prati veš
machine started spraying water all over
Mašina je počela prskati vodu na sve strane
and they didn't know and it just
a oni to nisu znali i to samo
destroyed their basement so it's just
uništili njihov podrum, tako da je jednostavno
like yeah I'm not for that but make me a
kao da, nisam za to, ali napravi me
coffee yeah that beer and bring it to me
kava da pivo i donesi mi ga
what I find interesting about this story
što mi se čini zanimljivo u ovoj priči
is that it's good yeah the stories it's
da je dobro da, priče su to
Google and they're making changes toward
Google i oni unose promjene u pravcu
users being able to control their
korisnici mogu kontrolirati svoje
privacy once again right but it's
privatnost još jednom u pravu, ali jeste
interesting that Google kind of missed
zanimljivo da je Google promašio
the boat on this initially I feel like
brod na ovom u početku mi se sviđa
Google has kind of always been ahead of
Google je nekako oduvek bio ispred
the game when it comes to that respect
igra kada je u pitanju to poštovanje
for privacy because they've kind of been
za privatnost jer su nekako bili
the front-runner mm-hmm so the fact that
prednji kotač mm-hmm pa činjenica da
they're trying to play catch-up now and
oni sada pokušavaju igrati nadoknadu
the fact that there was audio breaches
činjenica da je došlo do kršenja zvuka
where conversations were being shared
gde su se delili razgovori
I'm
Ja sam
going Wow Google come on yeah but I mean
ide Wow Google, da, ali mislim
it's good to see that they're making
dobro je vidjeti da oni prave
these changes you know but it's all of
ove promjene koje znate, ali sve su to
us think everybody's learning right
mi mislimo da svi pravilno uče
including Google obviously listen this
uključujući Google to očigledno slušaju
is why I don't let anyone else do
zato nikom drugom ne dopuštam
anything and I do I'm terrible at
bilo što i ja se grozno ponašam
delegating yeah because I'm afraid of
delegirati da, jer se bojim
someone making mistakes and so they've
neko pravi greške i tako ima
hired a third party company or maybe
unajmio treću kompaniju ili možda
they had staff that was doing this job
imali su osoblje koje je radilo ovaj posao
and that staff leaked the information
i to osoblje je procurilo informacije
yep yes that was meant to be internal
da da, to je trebalo da bude interno
like we need to improve our product now
kao da sada moramo poboljšati svoj proizvod
I have an Amazon device at home mm-hmm
Kod kuće imam uređaj Amazon mm-hmm
ditto so these features like that wasn't
tako da takve značajke nisu bile
meant for you and stuff mm-hmm
predviđeno za vas i stvari mm-hmm
are there equivalents on the Amazon
postoje li ekvivalenti na Amazoni
devices I'm seeing very similar kinds of
uređaji za koje vidim veoma slične vrste
enhancements happening ok Amazon and you
poboljšanja se događaju u redu Amazon i vi
know I've talked about it before but the
znam da sam razgovarao o tome ranije, ali ono
Amazon echo I have mine set in the app
Amazon odjek imam moj set u aplikaciji
to make a tone any time it hears it's
učiniti ton kad god čuje
activity and so sometimes you'll hear me
aktivnosti i tako ćete me ponekad čuti
if if it goes off here I just say cancel
ako ovdje ode, samo kažem odustani
so in the middle of a conversation
pa usred razgovora
somebody says that the action word by
neko kaže da je akcijska riječ od
accident and I hear do delete and I say
nesreća i čujem brisanje i kažem
cancel and it just now it comes
otkaži i to tek dolazi
naturally so right and I wish sometimes
naravno tako ispravno i to ponekad poželim
it will work in real life conversations
uspijevat će u stvarnim životnim razgovorima
with humans I convinced our kids that
s ljudima sam uvjerio našu djecu u to
ours is now Ansel Gekko yes you can
naš je sada Ansel Gekko da možeš
change your what no because oh because
promijenite ono što ne jer oh jer
we chose echo yeah as the as the name Oh
izabrali smo odjek da, kao ime Oh
but because you've got Gekko I convinced
ali zato što sam se uvjerio u Gekka
my kids to call it Gekko nice oh my god
moja djeca to zovu Gekko lijepo oh moj Bože
to change the name to get also the like
da biste promijenili ime da biste dobili i slično
Gekko that's cool
Gekko to je super